The main Lucia module

The functions here are responsible for initializing and quitting lucia, showing the game window, handle global events and so on. In addition, this part of lucia also contains most keyboard functions.
AudioBackend
AudioBackend(self, /, *args, **kwargs)
BASS
int([x]) -> integer int(x, base=10) -> integer
Convert a number or string to an integer, or return 0 if no arguments are given. If x is a number, return x.int(). For floating point numbers, this truncates towards zero.
If x is not a number or if base is given, then x must be a string, bytes, or bytearray instance representing an integer literal in the given base. The literal can be preceded by '+' or '-' and be surrounded by whitespace. The base defaults to 10. Valid bases are 0 and 2-36. Base 0 means to interpret the base from the string as an integer literal.
int('0b100', base=0) 4
FMOD
int([x]) -> integer int(x, base=10) -> integer
Convert a number or string to an integer, or return 0 if no arguments are given. If x is a number, return x.int(). For floating point numbers, this truncates towards zero.
If x is not a number or if base is given, then x must be a string, bytes, or bytearray instance representing an integer literal in the given base. The literal can be preceded by '+' or '-' and be surrounded by whitespace. The base defaults to 10. Valid bases are 0 and 2-36. Base 0 means to interpret the base from the string as an integer literal.
int('0b100', base=0) 4
OPENAL
int([x]) -> integer int(x, base=10) -> integer
Convert a number or string to an integer, or return 0 if no arguments are given. If x is a number, return x.int(). For floating point numbers, this truncates towards zero.
If x is not a number or if base is given, then x must be a string, bytes, or bytearray instance representing an integer literal in the given base. The literal can be preceded by '+' or '-' and be surrounded by whitespace. The base defaults to 10. Valid bases are 0 and 2-36. Base 0 means to interpret the base from the string as an integer literal.
int('0b100', base=0) 4
initialize
initialize(audiobackend=1)
Initialize lucia and the underlying graphic, audio, keyboard, interface engines
quit
quit()
Shutdown lucia and close underlying engines freeing up system resources
show_window
show_window(title='LuciaGame', size=(640, 480))
Shows the main game window on the screen, this is most likely called at the start of a game
process_events
process_events()
This processes events for the window This should be called in any loop, to insure that the window and application stays responsive
key_pressed
key_pressed(key_code)
Checks if a key was pressed down this frame (single key press) * key_code: A pygame.K_ key code
returns: True if the specified key kode was pressed, False otherwise.
key_released
key_released(key_code)
Checks if a key was released down this frame (single key release) * key_code: A pygame.K_ key code
returns: True if the specified key kode was released, False otherwise.
key_down
key_down(key_code)
Checks if a key is beeing held down. * key_code: A pygame.K_ key code
returns: True if the specified key kode is beeing held down, False otherwise.
key_up
key_up(key_code)
Check if a key isn't beeing held down (ie if it's not pressed and held) * key_code : A pygame.K_ key code
returns: True if key is not held down, False otherwise
lucia.data
Provides functions for easily manipulating textual or binary data. Currently includes encryption and compression.
unsupportedAlgorithm
unsupportedAlgorithm(self, /, *args, **kwargs)
raised when the user tries supplying an algorithm not specified in constants
output
An output which automatically selects the first available output on the system
outputs
Built-in mutable sequence.
If no argument is given, the constructor creates a new empty list. The argument must be an iterable if specified.
lucia.packfile
Lucia's resource pack module
This module will aid in the interaction with and creation of data files for storing game assets. A lucia resource file is a binary file format with the ability to have encryption and/or compression instituted on a per-file basis at creation time. Using the get method one may retrieve the contents of any file added to the pack, for example to be used in a memory load function of a sound system.
InvalidPackHeader
InvalidPackHeader(self, /, *args, **kwargs)
raised when the packs header is invalid
ResourceFileVersion
ResourceFileVersion(self, /, *args, **kwargs)
The version should only change if changes are introduced that breaks backwards compatibility
v1
int([x]) -> integer int(x, base=10) -> integer
Convert a number or string to an integer, or return 0 if no arguments are given. If x is a number, return x.int(). For floating point numbers, this truncates towards zero.
If x is not a number or if base is given, then x must be a string, bytes, or bytearray instance representing an integer literal in the given base. The literal can be preceded by '+' or '-' and be surrounded by whitespace. The base defaults to 10. Valid bases are 0 and 2-36. Base 0 means to interpret the base from the string as an integer literal.
int('0b100', base=0) 4
LoadPolicy
LoadPolicy(self, /, *args, **kwargs)
The load policy used when loading in data from a resource file
LOAD_ALL loads everything into ram. LOAD_INDEX only load in the filenames and where they are located on disk.
LOAD_ALL
int([x]) -> integer int(x, base=10) -> integer
Convert a number or string to an integer, or return 0 if no arguments are given. If x is a number, return x.int(). For floating point numbers, this truncates towards zero.
If x is not a number or if base is given, then x must be a string, bytes, or bytearray instance representing an integer literal in the given base. The literal can be preceded by '+' or '-' and be surrounded by whitespace. The base defaults to 10. Valid bases are 0 and 2-36. Base 0 means to interpret the base from the string as an integer literal.
int('0b100', base=0) 4
LOAD_INDEX
int([x]) -> integer int(x, base=10) -> integer
Convert a number or string to an integer, or return 0 if no arguments are given. If x is a number, return x.int(). For floating point numbers, this truncates towards zero.
If x is not a number or if base is given, then x must be a string, bytes, or bytearray instance representing an integer literal in the given base. The literal can be preceded by '+' or '-' and be surrounded by whitespace. The base defaults to 10. Valid bases are 0 and 2-36. Base 0 means to interpret the base from the string as an integer literal.
int('0b100', base=0) 4
ResourceFileItem
ResourceFileItem(self, name, content, compress, encrypt)
Internal object representing an item in the pack.
ResourceFile
ResourceFile(self, key, header=b'LURF', version=1)
The resource file object
You will interact with resource files through methods provided by this object. This object may have any number of instances, however only one instance should interact with a given file on the file system at a time.
load
ResourceFile.load(self, filename, policy=1)
Opens a resource file to be read.
This file will be checked for validity based on matching header, version, and a non-0 number of files. If one of these conditions fails, InvalidPackHeader will be raised. Otherwise this object will be loaded with the contents. :param filename: The file name to be read from the file system. :param policy (optional): The load policy to use, defaults to LoadPolicy.LOAD_ALL
save
ResourceFile.save(self, filename)
Saves data added to this object to a resource file.
When creating a resource file, this is the final method you would call. args: :param filename: The file name on disk to write to. Will be overwritten if already exists.
add_file
ResourceFile.add_file(self, name, compress=True, encrypt=True, internalname=None)
Adds a file on disk to the pack, optionally compressing and/or encrypting it.
args: :param name: The file name to read from. :param compress (boolean, optional): Whether compression should be applied to this file. Defaults to True. :param encrypt (boolean, optional): Whether encryption should be applied to this file. Defaults to True. :param internalname (optional): Internal file name to be used inside the pack. If None, the default, internal name will be same as name on disk.
get
ResourceFile.get(self, name)
[summary]
Args: name ([str]): The key to lookup in the data file
Returns: bytes or none: Returns the found result, or none if nothing with the specified key was found.
